# **Noufal P**

## **Software Developer**

Dubai, UAE

noufal677 ko9@indeedemail.com - +971 563879742

A highly resourceful, innovative, and competent software developer with three years experience in the layout, design and coding of software applications. Possessing considerable knowledge of the development of web applications and scripts using PHP programming language.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Software Developer**

VINAM SOLUTIONS PVT LTD -

2016-06 - 2017-12

Here are some of my recent projects in software development:

#### 1) Vinhrm

- Vinhrm is a hr management application software meant for effective employee management and to meet accurate finance management to grow a business.
- It provides all-in-all details of a company and employee recordings that helps for easy scheduling of work and task management.

Job Role

- Developed and implemented a complete dynamic system for payroll processing.
- Built in such a way to meet all technology changes.
- Wrote code for generating monthly report based on biometric and attendance data.
- Developed a calendar model for effective tracking of attendance and work hours.
- Designed and setup a notification and email message for leave and regularize actions.
- Implemented a import option for importing basic employee data with provision to choose which one is mapped with database field.
- Designed and implemented a salary revision method based on salary revision period.

Meanwhile there is a option to process payroll data individually.

- Designed and developed for multiple company management with in a organization.
- Contributed in providing suggestions to increase usability and productivity of the application software.

Technology used: PHP, Ajax, JavaScript, Angular.js, jQuery, MySQL, json, Google API,

Webservices, HTM, CSS, Git.

Framework used: Codeigniter.

Project Total Time: One and half year.

https://www.vinhrm.com/ https://ui.vinhrm.com/login

#### 2) Benchmark

• Benchmark Email offers an integrated, automated and robust feature set built to help the enterprise of any size.

- A powerfully simple and simply powerful email marketing solution designed to help to create and send compelling campaigns with ease.
- Bring customers in with signup forms that automatically fit into any space on site you want

Job Role:

- Unit testing and bug fixing.
- Optimizing gueries in order to reduce process time.
- Integration of Restful APIs.

Technology used: Core PHP, Ajax, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, Webservices, HTM, CSS, Git.

Project Total Time: Four Years. https://www.benchmarkcrm.com/ https://ui.benchmarkcrm.com/login

- 3) SAMT India annual conference registration site.
- Silex2017 is annual conference program for medical.laboratory students in south India.
- A registration site for generating ID card for students.

Job Role:

- Designed and developed a simple registration site for medical laboratory students with a provision to upload image of size less than 1mb.
- Admin can set a limit for the list of colleges so that payment verified members can register.
- Successfully printed over two thousand ID cards.

#### **Apprentice-Software Programmer**

OndemandHRM - Calicut, Kerala -

2015-06 - 2016-02

Calicut, Kerala.

Designation: Apprentice-Software Programmer. Work Period: From June 2015 to February 2016

Project: OnDemandHRM

- Hr management software for small medium enterprises.
- With the OnDemandHRM modules, you will find ease in the multi-faceted responsibility of managing human resources and more crucial role in the competition for hiring and retaining potential employees.

Job Role:

- Time sheet management.
- Designing and coding of employee management module.
- Bug fixing.
- All form validation with regular expression match.

Technology used: Linux, Apache, Mysql, PHP, HTML, CSS, javascript, ajax http://www.ondemandhrm.com

EDUCATION

### **B.TECH in CSE**

TKM Institute - Kollam, Kerala

2011 - 2015

### PLUS TWO in GHSS Vazhakkad

State Board Kerala - Malappuram, Kerala

2008 - 2010

### **SSLC in HIOHS Olavattur**

State Board Kerala - Malappuram, Kerala

2008

**SKILLS** 

Ajax, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, PHP

**LINKS** 

http://www.facebook.com/noufalpinju7

https://www.linkedin.com/in/noufal-perumbilavil-396140109

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

### COMPUTER KNOWLEDGE

Languages: Operating Systems:

- \* C \* Windows XP, Windows 7,8
- \* C++ \* Linux, Ubuntu
- \* MySQL
- \* PHP
- \* HTML5
- \* jQuery
- \* Ajax
- \* Javascript, Angular. js

**KEY SKILLS** 

- Good Communication Skills, Interpersonal Skills.
- Team Player, Fast learner, Analytic, Perfection, Patience, Punctual, .
- Reliable, Committed, result oriented hardworking, Optimistic
- Can easily establish a good rapport with people of any age and background
- Well-developed time management, organization and conflict resolution skills

• Works well in a fast paced team environment and independently with minimal supervision